以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将帮助MITOpenCourseWare继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
所以我周末都在努力工作
so I've worked hard over the weekend
弄清楚我上次做了什么
figured out what I was doing last time
和我在做什么这个时间和
and what I'm doing this time and
改进了笔记，所以你会得到一个新的
improved the notes so you'll get a new
关于上一讲和以后的一套笔记
set of notes on the last lecture and on
这个和我有点得到了
this one and I kind of got to got a
我们在做什么更好的画面和
better picture of what we're doing and
该委员会的目标是描述
that board is aiming to describe the
我们最后做的事情的大局
large picture of what we're doing last
时间，这次是最后一次
time and this time so last time was
关于a时的逆变化
about changes in a inverse when a
改变这个时间是关于变化的
changed this time is about changes in
特征值和奇异变化
eigenvalues and changes in singular
当你可以想象的变化时的价值观
values when a changes you can imagine
这是一个自然重要的情况
this is a natural important situation
矩阵移动，因此他们的
matrices move and therefore their
反转改变了它们的特征值变化
inverses change their eigenvalues change
他们的奇异价值会改变，而你就是这样
their singular values change and it you
希望有一个公式，所以我们确实有一个
hope for a formula well so we did have a
上次改变的公式
formula for last time for the change in
反矩阵这样和我一样
the inverse matrix so that's and I
没有得到每个U和V转置
didn't get every U and V transpose in
视频中的正确位置，但在或
the right place in the video but or in
笔记的第一个版本，但我
the first version of the notes but I
希望有这样的公式
hope that there'll be the formula that
Woodberrymorrison公式将是
that Woodberry morrison formula will be
正确
correct
这次确定，所以因此我不会回去了
this time ok so so I won't go back over
那部分
that part
但我也意识到还有另一个
but I realize also there there's another
问题是，我们能回答的时候
question that we can answer when the
改变时的变化非常小
change is very small when the change in
a是da或Deltaa的一个小变化和
a is da or Delta a of a small change and
这当然是微积分的意义所在
that's of course what calculus is about
所以我必须要有一些平行的主题
so I have to sort of parallel topics
这里的衍生物是什么？
here what is the derivative when the
它的变化是无穷小的
changes of of it is infinitesimal and
什么是实际的变化
what is the actual change when the
变化是有限大小没关系所以现在让我
change is finite size okay so now let me
说什么我们可以做，什么不能做
say what we can do and what we can't do
因为哦，我会先搞清楚
for oh I'll start out by figuring out
衍生物的反转是什么
what the derivative is for the inverse
这就像最后一次完成一样
so that's like completing the last time
对于无穷小的变化，我会移动
for infinitesimal changes then I'll move
关于特征值和特征值的变化
on to changes in the eigenvalues and
奇异的价值观，你不能
singular values and there you cannot
期待一个精确的公式，我们有一个我们有
expect an exact formula we had a we had
一个完全不同的公式
a formula that was exact apart from any
这个错别字，我们会找到一个公式
typos for this and we'll find a formula
为此，我们将找到一个公式
for this and we'll find a formula for
这一点，对于清楚，一次会
that and for that well that one will
来自这一个，所以这将是一个
come from this one so so this will be a
今天突出强调特征值如何
highlight today how do the eigen values
当矩阵改变但我们改变时
change when the matrix changes but we
我们无法与此平行
won't be able to do parallel to this we
我们将无法做到
won't be able to oh well we will be able
为你做些事情的变化有限
to do something for finite changes
这对数学来说很重要
that's important the mathematics would
必须继续打击它的问题
have to keep hitting it that problem
直到它到达某个地方所以我不会得到一个
until it got somewhere so I won't get an
改变的确切公式也是如此
exact formula for the change that's too
很多，但我会得到不平等有多大
much but I'll get inequalities how big
这种变化可能是我能说的
that change could be what can I say
关于它，所以这些是高度的
about it so these are that's highly
有趣的是我可以从这开始
interesting may I start with the
完成上一课的内容
completing the last lecture what
逆的导数，所以我
the derivative of the inverse so I'm
想到这里是什么设置了
thinking here so what's the setup the
设置是我的矩阵，取决于时间
setup is my matrix a depends on time on
T和它有一个逆逆
T and it has an inverse a inverse
取决于T，如果我知道这一点
depends on T and if I know this
换言之，如果我知道da
dependence in other words if I know da
DT矩阵的含义是多少
DT how much what how the matrix is
取决于T然后我希望我能
depending on T then I hope I could
弄清楚a的衍生物是什么
figure out what the derivative of a
逆是我们应该能够做到的
inverse is that we should be able to do
这就让我开始吧
this so let me just start with the it's
并不难，它补充了这个
not hard and it complements this one by
做微积分的情况下将
doing the calculus case the the
微小变化，所以我想要去
infinitesimal change so I want to get to
我得到了我能得到的
that I'm given I'm given I can figure
a的变化和我的工作是
out the change in a and my job is to
找到一个改变这个a的衍生物
find a change the derivative of this a
反之亦然所以这里很方便
and of a inverse okay so here's a handy
身份，我只是把它放在这里
identity and I just put this here so
这是我想要的有用身份
here's my useful identity I want to so
就像上次我开始用一个
as last time I start with a with a
有限变化其微积分总是如此
finite change its calculus always does
那个权利从一个三角洲T开始
that right starts with a delta T and
然后它变为零所以我在这里
then it goes to zero so so here I'm up
在完整的尺寸变化，所以我认为
at the full size change so I think that
这等于B逆a-Ba
this is equal to B inverse a minus B a
反过来，如果它是真的那就是a
inverse and that's if it's true it's a
非常酷的配方，看起来是真的
pretty cool formula and look it is true
因为在这个右手边我
because over on this right hand side I
有B反时间aa
have B inverse times a a
与身份相比，这是我的B.
versus the identity so that's my B
逆，我有减去B
inverse and I have the minus the B
逆B是有一个身份
inverse B is the identity there is a
反之，这是好的，所以这是一个
inverse it's good right so so that is a
从那个方面我们可以真正学习
from that well we I could actually learn
从那个等级的等级
from that the the rank of this equals
这是一个重点
the rank of this that's that's a point
我从大公式制造但现在
that I made from the big formula but now
我们可以从简单的公式中看到它
we can see it from easy formula I'm
假设B和a到处都是
assuming that B and a everywhere here
我假设a和b是可逆的
I'm assuming that a and b are invertible
当我乘以一个矩阵时
matrices so when i multiply by an
可变矩阵不会改变
invertible matrix that does not change
排名所以那些排名相同
the rank so the those have the same rank
但我会比那更进一步
but I'm gonna get further than that I
想找到这个没问题，那我该怎么办呢
want to find this okay so how do I go
我该如何继续这项工作呢
how do I go forward with that job to
很好地找到宇宙的衍生物
find the derivative of the universe well
我要让我打电话给这个
I'm gonna let I'm gonna call this a
在这里改变倒数
change in a inverse and over here
我会有V会是的，好吧，看对了
I'll have V will be yeah okay see right
是的，所以B逆将这是真的
yeah so B inverse will be this is really
这是一个加上Delta逆转而且这个
this is a plus Delta a inverse and this
很好，这是一个减B，所以这是
is well that's a minus B so that's
真的减去Delta一个减去右边
really minus Delta a minus right
变化是从A到B的变化
the change is from A to B is the change
我正在看这个区别
here I'm looking at this the difference
减去减B所以这是一个变化，
a minus B so it's minus a change and
在这里，我有一个反向我没有做过
here I have a inverse I haven't done
除了介绍这个Delta以外的任何东西
anything except to introduce this Delta
为了让我离开它并带来
for the and get me out of it and brought
三角洲现在好吗我想做
Delta in okay now I want to do
计算
calculations
所以我想B是你知道的
so I'm thinking of B as being you know a
有点儿，有点儿
little a little there's a sort of a
三角洲T和我双方要分
delta T and I'm gonna divide by both
如果我，deltaTI必须这样做
sides by delta T I have to do this if I
想要，现在我会让DeltaT归零
want and now I'll let Delta T go to zero
所以这是最终出现的微积分
so this is calculus appears finally are
我不会说我们的敌人微积分但是
I won't say our enemy calculus but but
有一种类似的竞争
there's a sort of like competition
线性代数与微积分之间的关系
between linear algebra and calculus for
对于大学数学微积分已经有了
for college mathematics calculus has had
这是太多的时间和注意力
far far too much time and attention it's
喜欢它有三到四个学期
like it gets three or four semesters of
微积分给没有得到任何人的人
calculus for people who don't get any
线性代数我很高兴这不会出现
linear algebra I'm glad this won't be on
视频，但我担心它无论如何
the video but I'm afraid it will anyway
当然微积分就好了
of course calculus is fine in its place
好吧所以现在这里的地方让Deltat
okay so here's its place now let Delta t
归零，那么这个等式是什么
go to zero so what does this equation
成为它刚刚结束，每个人都知道
become it just ends and everybody knows
随着极限的ΔT去
that as the limit as delta T goes to
零我更换三角洲的由三角洲如此
zero I replace Delta's by the Delta so
这个Delta除以deltaT有
this Delta a divided by delta T that has
每个顶部都有意义的意思
a meaning each the top has a meaning and
底部有一个平均值，但随后在
the bottom has a mean but then in the
限制它是一个有意义的比例
limit it's a ratio that has a meaning so
da本身
da by itself
我没有附加含义
I don't attach a meaning to that's
无穷小这是极限所以那是
infinitesimal it's the limit so that's
为什么我想要三角洲的delta，所以我
why I wanted a delta over a delta so I
可以做微积分所以现在发生的事情
could do calculus so what happens now as
deltaT变为零，当然也是
delta T goes to zero and of course as
deltaT变为零，携带Delta
delta T goes to zero that carries Delta
a到零，这样就变成了逆
a to zero so that becomes a inverse and
这种方法与deltaT相比如何？
what does this approach as delta T goes
为零
to zero
da/dt用那个减号哦我有
da/dt with that minus sign oh I've got
要记住减号减号是
to remember the minus sign minus sign is
在这里-我带出了减号
in here - I'm bringing out the minus
那么这就像我们所做的那样
sign then this was a inverse as we had
和那个da/dt那是相反的
and that da/dt and that's a inverse
这就是我们的公式一个很好的公式，
that's our formula a nice formula which
某种属于人们的知识
sort of belongs in people's knowledge
你认识到如果a是1比1
you recognize that if a was a 1 by 1
矩阵我们可以称之为X而不是a
matrix we could call it X instead of a
如果a，如果有一个1乘1的矩阵X则
if a if a there's a 1 by 1 matrix X then
我正在看到的公式
I'm seeing the formula for the
X的1的导数写一个逆
derivative of 1 over X write a inverse
只是一个1比1的情况，它只是X超过1所以
just a 1 by 1 case it's just 1 over X so
1或TI的衍生物应该
the derivative of 1 or maybe T I should
如果a只是T那么说
be saying if if a is just T then the
T相对于T的导数为1
derivative of 1 over T with respect to T
我是正方形，是正方形的负1
is is minus 1 over T squared right I've
只是逐个案例，我们知道这是
just the one by one case we know that's
什么是微积分，现在我们能够做到
what calculus does and now we're able to
通过n个案例来做那个就是那个
do that n by n case so that's that's
就像好，然后是先生
just like good and then it's it sir
平行于这样的公式
parallel to formulas like this which are
这个deltaa没有变为0的地方
where this delta a is not gone to 0 it's
全尺寸但低级别
full size but low-rank
这实际上就是公式
that was the point actually the formula
是它会适用，如果排名
would be it would apply if the rank
虽然不低，但利息却很低
wasn't low but the interest is in low
秩
rank
我们对此有好处吗？
are we good for this that's really the
完成最后一次讲座
completion of last times lecture with
与衍生品确定好来回来
with derivatives ok ok come in come back
来到这里新的东西现在lambdas
to here to the new thing now lambdas
让我们关注lambdas特征值如何
let's focus on lambdas eigenvalues how
当特征值改变时
does the eigen value change when the
矩阵改变请问该特征值
matrix changes how does the eigen value
当矩阵发生变化时我会改变
change when the matrix changes so I have
至
to
可能性一个是小变化的时候
possibilities one is small change when
我在做微积分，我让一个
I'm doing calculus and I'm letting a
deltaT变为零，另一个变满
delta T go to zero the other is full
大小顺序改变我不会改变的地方
size order one change where I will not
能够给你一个公式为
be able to give you a formula for the
新的lambdas但我能告诉你
new lambdas but I'll be able to tell you
关于他们的重要事实就是如此
important facts about them so that's so
现在这是今天的演讲
this is this is today's lecture now you
可以说是完成了
could say that's the completion of
周五的演讲怎么样d拉姆达DT
Friday's lecture what about D lambda DT
这是一个很好的公式，这是一个证据
it's a nice formula and it's a proof is
好玩-我对这个证据感到非常高兴
fun - I was very happy about this proof
好吧所以我猜微积分出现了
okay so I guess calculus is showing up
在这个中间板上，我该怎么做
here on this middle board so how do I
从特征值开始
start with the eigenvalues well start
我所知道的，所以这些都是事实
with what I know so so these are facts
你可以说，我必须得到
you could say that I have to get the
特征值，当然
eigenvalues into it and of course
特征值必须带有特征
eigenvalues have to come with eigen
矢量，所以我会再次使用它
vectors so I'll again use a of T it'll
取决于T和特征向量
be depending on T and an eigen vector
这取决于T是一个特征值
that depends on T is an eigen value that
取决于T倍的特征向量
depends on T times an eigen vector that
取决于我们的事实
depends on T great a fact one that we
计划采取某种方式的衍生物
plan to take the derivative of somehow
还有第二个事实
there's also a second fact that comes
在这里发挥什么是交易
into play here what's the deal on the
他们就是转置的特征值
eigenvalues of a transpose they're the
转置的特征值是相同的
same the eigenvalues of a transpose are
与a的特征值相同
the same as the eigen values of a are
特征向量通常不同
the eigenvectors the same not usually of
当然，如果矩阵是对称的话
course if the matrix was symmetric then
a和转置是一样的
a and a transpose are just the same
所以他们会有这样的转置
thing so they would have so a transpose
通常会有那个特征值
would have that eigenvalue but generally
特征向量，但它通常有一个
eigenvector but it generally it has a
不同的特征向量，它真的
different eigenvector and it really to
保持它与这一个分开
keep it sort of separate from this one
让我们称之为它，它会有相同的
let's call it y it'll have the same
特征值我打算打电话
eigenvalue I'm going to call
为什么，但我要把它变成行向量
why but I'm gonna make it a row vector
因为转置是代替的
because a transpose is what instead of
写下转置我会留下来的
writing down a transpose I'm gonna stay
用a但是把特征值放在
with a but put the eigenvalue on the
左边所以这里是特征值
left side so here here's the eigenvalue
左边的一个特征向量，它有
eigenvector for a on the left and it has
相同的特征值时间
the same eigenvalue times that
特征向量，但我在向量中是一个
eigenvector but that i in vector is a
我当然非常喜欢这个
row I am very of course this is an
行之间的行相等于我的行
equality between rows a row times my
矩阵给出一行，这就是
matrix gives a row so that's the
它具有相同的特征值
eigenvalues of that it has the same
特征值所以这是完全的
eigenvalue so this is this is totally
平行于完全平行和
parallel to that totally parallel and
也许有点不太确定
maybe there's sort of less definitely
不太常见，但这只是一回事
less seen but it's just the same thing
对于你使用每个人看到的转置
for a transpose you use everybody sees
如果我改变这个等式，那么我就是
if I transpose this equation then I've
得到的东西看起来像那样但是
got something that looks like that but
我现在宁愿这样做了
I'd rather have it this way now one more
关于我需要的这一事实的事情
thing about these one more fact I need
我必须要有一些
there's there has to be some I some
规范化应该怎样多久
normalization how long how what should
是现在X可能的长度
be the length of the right now X could
有任何长度Y可以有任何长度
have any lengths Y could have any length
并且有一种自然的正常化
and there's a natural normalization
这是y转置时间X等于
which is y transpose times X equal to
规范化的一个并不能说明
one that normalizes the to doesn't tell
我是X的长度还是Y的长度
me the length of X or the length of Y
但它告诉我他们说的关键
but it tells me the key saying they're
两者的长度，所以我所拥有的
lengths of both so what I've what I've
得到那里跟踪一个本征
got there is tracking along one eigen
值和它的一对特征向量和
value and it's pair of eigen vectors and
你总是欢迎想到的
you're always welcome to think of the
当y和X相同时的对称情况
symmetric case when y and X are the same
然后我会叫他们问我哦
and then I would call them Q oh well I
如果它是对称的，它会称它们为Q.
would call them Q if it was a symmetric
矩阵，但如果是的话，我会的
matrix but I would have if yeah so if
它是一个对称矩阵，我称之为
it's a symmetric matrix I would call the
两个特征向量都称为q
both eigenvectors would be called q
这就是说队列是一个
and this would be saying that queue is a
单位向量，所以这是所有的东西
unit vector right so this is all stuff
我们知道，实际上也许我应该
we know and actually maybe I should
用矩阵表示法写出来就是这样
write it in in matrix notation just so
因为这是重要的，如果这是一个
cuz it's important so if that's for one
特征向量这适用于所有人
eigenvector this is for all of them at
一旦每个人都与它的x是
once everybody's with it the x's are the
我X的列需要仔细考虑AMDA是
columns of X and I need to mull aMDA is
lambdas的对角矩阵和它
the diagonal matrix of lambdas and it
必须坐在右边这样才能
has to sit on the right so that it will
将这些列相乘，这就像
multiply those columns so this is like
一切的一切特征向量一次
all all eigenvectors at once
这将是什么意思
what would this one be this would be
像Y转置等于Y转置
like Y transpose a equals a Y transpose
Ÿs等于O和可能这些都是
Y s equals o and probably these are
乘以它有趣我不想
multiplied it's funny I don't want to
如果我写Y，那就说我感觉不对劲
put what I'm I feel wrong if I write Y
像这里一样在X转置
transpose here like here the X was on
右侧和左侧和专辑一个
the right and on the left and album one
哦，是的，你转置是的好，所以什么
oh it yeah y transpose yeah okay so what
我把lambdaY转置，做什么
do I put lambda Y transpose and what do
我把这个翻译成了什么
I put here what does this translate to
如果我这是一个特征向量
if I if this was for a one eigenvector
对于他们所有人来说，它就是这样
for all of them at once it's just gonna
翻译为Y转X等于
translate to Y transpose X equal the
身份这是非常基本的东西但是
identity this is pretty basic stuff but
不知怎的，我们并不总是
stuff somehow we don't always
一定看还好那些是关键
necessarily see okay those are the key
事实，现在我打算采取
facts and now I plan to take the
衍生物带有衍生物
derivative take the derivative with
尊重lambda哦，我可以推导出来
respect to lambda oh okay I can derive
多了一个事实，所以这
one more fact so this
配方这是配方一的公式之一
formula this is formula one formula one
只是说我会得到什么，如果我打这个上
just says what do I get if I hit this on
Y转置左边我可以做那个Y.
the left by Y transpose can I do that Y
T等于TX的TX的转置
transpose of T a of T X of T equals
T的lambda是我们的数字
lambda of T that's us that's a number so
我总是可以把它带到前面
I can always bring that out but in front
内积的矢量符号
of the inner product the vector notation
你恳求的那样对你有好处吗？
are you good for that I'm pleading like
我所做的一切都完全没问题
everything I've done is totally okay and
现在我对此有所改进
now I have a improvement to make on this
右手边哪个是y
right hand side which is so what is y
转置时间X它是1所以让我们
transpose times X it's 1 so let's
记住它是1，所以换句话说我
remember that it's 1 so in other words I
有一个lambda的T的公式
have got a formula for lambda of T the
随着时间改变矩阵的特征值
eigen value as time changes the matrix
改变其本征值的变化
changes its eigen values change
按照这个公式其
according to this formula its
特征向量根据此变化
eigenvectors change according to this
公式，它是左特征向量
formula and it's left eigenvectors
根据那个公式改变不是
change according to that formula isn't
所以这里的一切都是如此
that so where everything here is
在板上，现在有什么意义
aboveboard and now what's the point
关键是我会发现这个
the point is I'm gonna find this the
派生所以我要接受
derivative so I'm going to take the
该等式的衍生物，看看是什么
derivative of that equation and see what
我明白了
I get
这就是那个公式
that's that'll be the formula for the
特征值的导数和它的
derivative of an eigen value and it's
令人惊讶的是，它并不是那么广泛
it's amazingly it's not that widely
知道它当然是经典的但是
known it's of course it's classical but
它并不总是课程的一部分所以这些
it's not always part of courses so these
这是随着时间变化矩阵的变化
this is as time varies the matrix varies
a因此它的特征值
a and therefore its eigenvalues
它是特征向量，所以我们是
and it's eigenvectors very so we're
会发现DlambdaDT是一个级别
gonna find D lambda DT it's one level of
更难找到DXDT那个
difficulty more to find DX DT that the
特征向量的导数或
derivative of the eigenvector or the
特征值的二阶导数
second derivative of the eigenvalue
虽然那些人聚在一起
though those kind of come together and
我不会去那里我就要去做
I'm not gonna go there I'm just gonna do
这里有一件好事
the one great thing here take the
我应该做那个方程的导数
derivative of that equation shall I do
它在那边所以我们去，所以我想
it over there so here we go so I want to
计算DlambdaDT，我正在使用它
compute D lambda DT and I'm using this
lambda的公式，所以我有
formula for lambda there so I've got
依赖于T和我的三件事
three things that depend on T and I'm
采取他们的产品的衍生物
taking the derivative of their product
所以我要正确使用产品规则
so I'm gonna use the product rule right
现在它需要我将应用该产品
now it takes a I'll apply the product
统治那个衍生物好吧
rule to that derivative okay
取第一个人的衍生物
take the derivative of the first guy
X次乘以衍生物的次数
times a times X take the derivative of
第二个人和第二个人相遇
the second guy times the second guy and
牛逼DX的TA的第三个家伙ÿ转
the third guy Y transpose of T a of T DX
DT好吧我们距离一分钟一分钟
DT okay we are one minute away from a
伟大的公式，我真的很高兴，如果
great formula and I'm really happy if
你让我这说的是，
you allow me to say it that that the
公式来自于采取
formula comes by just putting taking
那些我们知道的事实
those facts we know putting them
我们一起进入这个表达
together into this expression that we
也知道，这就像lambda
also know and that this is like lambda
等于X逆ax
equals X inverse ax
这是对角化的事情然后
that's diagonalizing thing and then
采取衍生物所以我得到了什么
taking the derivative so what do I get
如果我这个术语能很好地利用这个衍生物
if I take that derivative well this term
我会继续保持，好像我不会去
I'm going to keep like I'm not going to
玩弄每个人都很清楚
play with that everybody's clear that's
这里的数字是ADT的矩阵
a number here's a matrix the ADT is a
矩阵我得到的导数
matrix the derivative I take the
它的衍生物在这里的每一个条目
derivative of it every entry in a here's
它是一个列向量，它的特征向量
it's a column vector its eigen vector
这是Rho时间的行向量
and here's a row vector so Rho times
矩阵时间列是第一个
matrix times column is a number one by
一个，实际上这是我的答案
one and actually that's my answer
那是我的回答所以我这么说
that's my answer so I'm saying that
这两个词相互抵消了
these two terms cancel each other out
这两个方面相加为零，并且
those two terms add to zero and that
这是正确的答案
this is the right answer for for the
衍生物
derivative
这是一个很好的公式，所以找到
that's a nice formula so to find the
您采用的特征值的导数
derivative of an eigen value you take
矩阵改变你的速度
the rate the matrix is changing you
乘以俄勒冈州的矢量和
multiply by the Oregon vector and by the
左特征向量它给你一个数字
left eigen vector it gives you a number
那就是DlambdaDT好吧，为什么呢
and that's the D lambda DT okay so why
那两个家伙加零是不是
do those two guys add to zero that's
那就是剩下的一切
that's all that remains here and then
这个主题以这个好结束了
this topic is ended with this nice
公式好，所以我想简化它
formula okay so I want to simplify that
简化并表明他们取消了
simplify that and show that they cancel
彼此没关系，所以什么是斧头它的lambda
each other okay so what is ax its lambda
X所以这个家伙只不过是它的lambda
X so this guy is nothing but it's lambda
这取决于课程时间的时间dy
that depends on time of course times dy
DTDY转置DT我只是复制
DT D Y transpose DT I'm just copying
那斧子拉姆达X
that ax is lambda X
抱歉，我不是故意要看那个
sorry I didn't mean to make that look
那个斧头很难用lambdaX和我
hard okay with that ax is lambda X and I
我非常安全，因为lambda只是
am perfectly safe because lambda is just
一个数字，将它带到左边
a number to bring it out to the left so
它没有得到它看起来不像它
it's not getting doesn't look like it's
在路上和另一个怎么样
in the way and what about this other
长期所以我有ý转AUÿ
term so I have y transpose au y
转置一个什么是Y.
transpose a what's that what's Y
移调这就是组合
transpose a that's the combination that
我知道Y转换一个让Y就是那个
I know Y transpose a a a let Y is that
左特征向量y转置a带来
left eigenvector y transpose a is brings
出一个lambda所以这也带来了一个
out a lambda so this also brings out a
lambdatimesytransposexdx/dt好吧我
lambda times y transpose x dx/dt okay I
只需使用ax等于lambdaX即可
just use ax equal lambda X there that
现在什么都不是，我该怎么办
was really nothing now what do I do
你能不能让我想零吗？
can you I want this to be zero can you
看到它正在发生它是一个伟大的
see it happening it's a it's a great
很高兴看到它发生得如此做什么
pleasure to see it happening so what do
我在这里现在是我的第一步
I have here what's my first step now
带来会把lambda带到那个外面
bring would bring lambda outside that's
不是零，我们不知道那是什么
not zero we don't know what that is
把lambda带到那里时间
bring lambda outside there times the
因为一些奇妙的原因所以整个事情
whole thing so for some wonderful reason
我相信这个数字是一个
I believe that this number which is a
第一列的滚动时间乘以a
roll times at column a row times a
列两届那里，我相信他们
column two terms there I believe they
互相敲打他们那个
knock each other out and they that
结果为零，为什么我为什么呢？
result is zero and why why because I
回到这是这个董事会的
come back to the this is this board has
所有我知道的，这就是为什么要转置
all that I know and here's why transpose
时间X等于1，这有何帮助
times X equal one and how does that help
我，因为我在那里看到的
me because what I'm seeing in that
在那个方格和那些括号是
square in that and those brackets is the
Y的导数转置X.
derivative of Y transpose X
所以它是一个人的衍生物
so it's the derivative of one therefore
零，所以这是它的衍生物
zero so this is the derivative of one it
等于零这两个术语敲每个
equals zero those two terms knock each
其他的，只留下美好的名词
other out and leave just the nice term
我们看到的是衍生物
that we're seeing so the derivative of
特征值只是为了有一个
the eigenvalue just just to have one
在我们离开它之前先看看它
more look at it before we leave it the
特征值的导数就是这个
derivative of the eigenvalue is this
公式是它的速率
formula it's the rate at which the
矩阵正在改变时代
matrix is changing times the
有时左右的特征向量
eigenvectors on right and left sometimes
他们被称为正确的特征向量
they're called the right eigenvector in
在时间t的左特征向量
the left eigenvector at at the time t
是的，所以我们没有看到这一点
yeah so a is so we're not seeing in this
换言之，lambdaDT不是我
d lambda DT in other words does is not I
不需要我得到一个很好的配方
don't need to I get a nice formula which
不涉及的衍生物
doesn't involve the derivative of the
特征向量，如果我是它的美丽
eigenvector that's the beauty of it if I
想上去应该迈出下一步
want to go up should take the next step
我本周末试过，但如果这是一团糟
I tried this weekend but it's a mess if
这是我的意思
it would be to take there so I've this
是我的公式和DlambdaDT等于
is my formula and D lambda DT equals
这个和我可以采取下一个衍生物
this and I can take the next derivative
这一点，并会涉及第二
of that and it will involve the second
天DT正确，但也会
day DT squared right but it will also
实际上涉及DXDT和dyDT
involve DX DT and dy DT and it in fact
伪逆甚至显示出它
the pseudo-inverse even shows up it's
这是另一个步骤，我不会去
it's a another step and I'm not going
那是因为我们拥有最好的
that far because we've got the the best
公式那里好吧所以现在有了
formula there okay so now that has
我回答了这个问题
answered this question and I could
以同样的方式回答这个问题
answer that question the same way it
将涉及转置a和
would involve a transpose a and the
奇异向量而不是涉及到
singular vectors instead of involving a
并且特征向量可能是a
and the eigenvectors maybe that's a
适合的运动我不知道我没有
suitable exercise I don't know I haven't
自己做了我想做的就是这个
done it myself what I want to do is this
现在，我们可以说什么可以说
now now it's say what can we say about
特征值的变化，我会
the change in the eigenvalue and I'll
首先要保留特征值
just stay first of all with eigenvalues
当改变就像Rank1那样
when the change is like Rank 1 that way
这是一个完美的例子
this is a perfect example when the
变化是等级1所以所以我真的如此
change is Rank 1 so so so I'm really so
关于特征值我们能说些什么呢？
what can we say about the eigenvalues
让我们把最大的顶部
let's take the top the largest
特征值或所有这些都是特征值
eigenvalue or all of them all of them
lambdaJ他们都加了一个等级
lambda J all of them of a plus a rank
一个矩阵UV转置让我做
one matrix UV transpose oh let me make
它让我们，让我们在这里做一个漂亮的情况下，
it let's let's do the nice case here a
很好的情况，因为如果我允许一般
nice case because if I allow a general
矩阵我不得不担心它
matrix a I have to worry about does it
有足够的特征向量你知道吗
have enough eigenvectors you know can it
将所有那些东西对齐化
diagonalize all that stuff let's make
让我们使它成为一个对称矩阵和
let's make it a symmetric matrix and
让我们使等级一变化对称
let's make the rank one change symmetric
也因此，问题是我能说什么
too so the question is what can I say
关于排名之后的特征值
about the eigenvalues of after a rank
一次改变，这不是微积分
one change so again this isn't calculus
现在因为我正在做的改变
now because the change that I'm making
完全是一个真正的向量而不是
is as fully as is a true vector and not
差别好，我不会
a differential okay and I'm not going to
具有用于新的固有的精确配方
have an exact formula for the new eigen
我说的价值，但我要去做什么
values as I said but what I am going to
做的是写下美好的事实
do is write down the beautiful facts
那是众所周知的，在这里他们
that are known about that and here they
首先是特征值
are so first of all the eigen values are
按降序排列，我们使用降序
in descending order we use descending
奇异值的顺序让我们使用它们
order for singular values let's use them
也是因为λ为1的特征值
also for an eigen value so lambda 1
大于等于λ2更大
is greater equal to lambda 2 greater
等于lambda3等等
equal lambda 3 and so on
哦，给我给我一个啊给我一个
Oh give me give me a yeah give me an
你有什么想法？
idea well what do you expect from from
将这一变化排在第一位
that rank one change so that that
变化等级1你能告诉我了吗？
changes Rank 1 can you tell me any more
关于那个改变你转移什么
about that change you you transpose what
一种矩阵是uu转置它的
kind of a matrix is uu transpose it's
等级1，但我们可以说更多
rank 1 but we can say more
这是当然的负鼠埃特里克，它是
it is possum Ettrick of course and it is
是的积极半肯定的积极
yeah positive semi definite positive
半确定这是一个积极的变化
semi definite this is a positive change
uutranspose是典型的排名1
uu transpose is the typical rank 1
正半确定它不可能
positive semi definite it couldn't be
肯定的，因为它只有
positive definite because it's only got
等级1本征是什么的
Rank 1 what are the eigen what's the
那个矩阵的特征向量是的，是的
eigenvector of that matrix yeah let's
只是为什么不能在这里我们可以通过两种做到这一点
just why not here we can do this in two
秒
seconds
所以uutranspose这是一个矩阵我
so uu transpose that's a matrix I'm
请您想想，这是一个
asking you to think about and it's a
全n乘n矩阵列乘一行
full n by n matrix column times a row
告诉我那个矩阵的特征向量
tell me an eigenvector of that matrix
是的，如果我把你的矩阵乘以你
yes you if I multiply my matrix by you
我得到了什么，我得到一些数字
I get what do I get I get some number
时间U和那个数字是什么lambda
times U and what is that number lambda
是lambda恰好是你的转置
is that lambda happens to be u transpose
你和那是什么不同
U and what is the so that's different
来自uutranspose这是一个矩阵
from uu transpose this was a matrix
现在每个人都使用18超过65
everybody uses 18 over 6 5 now that's a
号码，你能告诉我什么
number and what can you tell me about
那个数字
that number
它更大更好
it is greater well even more greater
比0大，因为这是真的
than 0 greater because this is a true
矢量所以这大于0
vector so this is greater than 0 it's
所有其他的唯一特征值
the only eigenvalue all the other
的那秩的特征值
eigenvalues of the of that of that rank
一个矩阵是0但是一个非零
one matrix are 0 but the one non-zero
本征
eigen
价值在好的方面结束了它就是你
value is over on the plus side it's you
转你，我们都意识到，作为
transpose you we all recognize that as
U的长度肯定是平方的
the lengths of U squared it's certainly
积极的，所以我们确实有一个积极的半
positive so we do have a positive semi
确定矩阵你的猜测是什么
definite matrix what would your guess be
对一个特征值的影响
of the effect on the eigenvalues of a so
所以我回到我真正的问题我
so I'm coming back to my real problem I
可以的值很抱歉是的我有一个
can values of s sorry yes I have a
对称矩阵我说的是对称的
symmetric matrices I'm saying symmetric
如果我有一个对称的话，你的猜测是什么？
what is your guess if I have a symmetric
矩阵和我添加uutranspose做什么
matrix and I add on uu transpose what do
你想象那对特征值有影响
you imagine that does to the eigenvalues
你会说得对，就这么说吧
you're gonna get it right just say it
s的特征值会发生什么
what happens to the eigenvalues of s if
我加上uutranspose他们将会
I add on uu transpose they will they'll
更积极的他们会上升这是一个
be more positive they'll go up this is a
积极的事情就像添加17
positive thing it's like adding 17 to
因此它会向上移动
something right it moves up so therefore
我相信是这样的，现在我已经这样了
what I believe is so these now I have so
是的我有两套特征值
yeah I've got two sets of eigenvalues
现在一个是另一个的S参数
now one is the argument of s the other
是特征值的不同
is the eigenvalues the different
s的特征值所以我不能称之为
eigenvalues of s so what I can't call
他们两个lambda表达式或我有麻烦所以
them both lambdas or I'm in trouble so
让我让我开始，所以我会打电话给
let me let me start so I'll call the
需要这样的另一个你最喜欢的
need so one other do you have a favorite
其他希腊字母的特征值
other Greek letter for the eigenvalues
只要你说一个，你的伽玛好吗？
of s gamma okay as long as you say a
希腊字母我有一些想法如何
Greek letters I have some idea how to
写Zeta在我看来就好像
write Zeta it seems to me like the
世界上最难写的信和
world's toughest letter to write and
电气工程师可以冷静地冲洗
electrical engineers can coolly flush
阿尔法泽塔，但我从未成功过
alpha Zeta but like I've never succeeded
所以你说的好吧
so so all right what did you say
伽玛J原来没关系所以那些
gamma J of the original okay so those
是原始的特征值
are the eigenvalues of the original
这些是特征值
these are the eigenvalues of the
修改过，我们期待着lambdas
modified and we're expecting the lambdas
要大
to be big
比起gammas哦，它只是一个
than the gammas oh it's just a
定性陈述，这是真的
qualitative statement and it's true
每个lambda都大于gamma哦
each lambda is bigger than the gamma oh
对不起是啊是的每个lambda加入
sorry yeah yeah each lambda by adding
这个东西，lambda比大
this stuff the lambdas are bigger than
所以我就写的是lambda表达式
so I'll just write that lambdas are
比gammas大，那是一个
bigger than gammas and that's a
我们可以证明的基本事实
fundamental fact which we could prove
而多了几分被称为当然的了
but a little more is known of course the
问题是多大可以多大
question is how much bigger how much can
他们做得更好，我不相信
they be way bigger well I don't believe
他们可能会更大更多
they could be bigger by more than more
比我自己的那个数字还有
than that number myself but there's
那里有更好的消息
there's there's better news than that so
lambdas比gammas大
the lambdas are bigger than the gammas
所以lambda1大于gamma1所以
so lambda 1 is bigger than gamma 1 so
这是SPlusuu
this is of this is the S Plus u u
转置矩阵，这些是
transpose matrix and this these are the
S矩阵λ1的特征值是
eigenvalues of the S matrix lambda 1 is
大于伽玛1，但看起来是什么
bigger than gamma 1 but look what's
发生在这一行文本中我是
happening in this line of text here I'm
说λ2是λ2
saying that gamma 1 that lambda 2 is
小于伽马1是不是工整
smaller than gamma 1 isn't that neat the
特征值上升，但它们不仅仅是
eigenvalues go up but they don't just
喜欢去任何地方，这就是所谓的
like go anywhere and that's called
隔行扫描
interlacing
所以这是其中一个很棒的
so this is one of those wonderful
使你的心快乐的定理
theorems that makes your heart happy
那个想法，如果我做一个等级
that that the idea that if I do a rank
一个改变然后我和它是一个
one change then the I and it's a
然后积极改变特征值
positive change then the eigen values
增加，但他们不增加新的
increase but they don't increase the new
特征值低于新的秒
eigen value is below the new second
特征值它不会传递旧的
eigen value it doesn't pass up the old
第一个特征值和新的第三个
first eigen value and the new third
特征值不会过时
eigen value doesn't pass up the old
第二个本征是的，是的，所以那是
second eigen does yeah yeah so that's
这就是隔行扫描定理
the that's the interlacing theorem that
与着名群众的名字相关联
associated with the names of famous mass
那些人当然是你必须的
guys that's just of course you have to
在我们写作的时候说这很漂亮
say that's beautiful while we're writing
下来这样一个定理猜猜是什么
down such a theorem make a guess of what
如果我做一个等级，定理就是
the theorem would be if I do a rank to
改变假设我做了一个是对不起的
change suppose I do an A yes sorry s
保持对称，我排名第一
staying symmetric and I do a rank one
改变但是我也做了一个等级
change but then I also do a rank to
改变说Ww转置好，所以是什么
change say W w transpose okay so what's
这里的交易我对此有何了解
the deal here what do I know about that
三角洲的变化矩阵在这里我
the change matrix the Delta s here I
知道它的排名是2我假设你和
know it's rank is 2 I'm assuming you and
W不是这样的
W were not in the same direction so
这是一个2级矩阵，你可以做什么
that's a rank 2 matrix and what can you
告诉我有关它的特征值
tell me about the eigenvalues of that
秩2矩阵，因此它有n个特征值
Rank 2 matrix so it's got n eigenvalues
因为它是N×n矩阵但是如何
because it's an N by n matrix but how
它也有许多非零特征值
many nonzero eigenvalues has it got too
因为它的等级是等级告诉的
because it's rank is to the rank tells
你是非零特征值的数量
you the number of nonzero eigenvalues
当矩阵是对称的时，它不会
when matrices are symmetric it doesn't
告诉你，矩阵是否足够
tell you enough if matrices are
非对称特征值可能很奇怪
unsymmetric eigenvalues can be weird so
保持对称，这样就可以了
stay symmetric here ok so that that
这有一个Chazz两个非零的特征值
this has a Chazz two nonzero eigenvalues
你能告诉我他们的标志吗？
and can you tell me their sign
什么是矩阵正面
what is that matrix positive
当然，半定是的，它是
semi-definite yes of course it is of
当然所以这是，而且这是和
course so this was and this was and
肯定是
together it certainly is
所以现在我增加了两个积极的排名
so now I've added a rank two positive
确定正半正定矩阵
definite positive semi definite matrix
现在我只是不打算重写
and now just I'm not going to rewrite
此行，但你会期望
this line but what would you expect to
是的，你会期待特征值
be true you would expect the eigenvalues
增加但是lambda三有多大
increase but how big could lambda three
很抱歉伽玛是的所以伽玛2让我们
are sorry gamma yeah so gamma 2 let's
遵循伽玛2所以现在好吧也许我
follow gamma 2 so so now well maybe I
应该使用希腊人的另外两个
should use another two the Greeks have
除了lambda和gamma之外的任何其他字母
any other letters than lambda and gamma
谁看到了这一切，谁知道，每个
who see all of that who knows that each
一个我可以写alpha好的alpha是的
one I can write alpha good alpha yes
alpha右边所以alpha作为特征alpha
alpha right so alpha as the eigen alpha
是这个环的特征值
is the eigenvalues of this this ring to
现在改变好我将成为什么样的人
change okay now what am I going to be
能说我可以说些什么
able to say can I say anything about
当然这很好，alpha1更大
this well of course alpha 1 is bigger
比lambda1大于I
than lambda 1 which was bigger than I
意思是我可以测量正确的上升我是
mean I can measure going up right I'm
增加肯定或正面
adding positive definite or positive
半定的东西，我无能为力
semi definite stuff there's no way I can
伙计们可以开始贬低我了
guys can start going down on me
所以alpha1大于或等于
so alpha 1 is greater or equal to the
拉姆达1，它方才秩一
lambda 1 which had just a rank one
变化大于等于
change which is greater equal to the to
MU是mugammagamma1，它是
the MU was it mu gamma gamma 1 which is
a，那是的，等等现在好了
a and that's yeah and so on okay now
让我们看看alpha1是
let's see is alpha 1 is
比我更大的阿尔法
one bigger than alpha what am i
奋力在这里写下来好
struggling to to write down here well
我能说什么才能说得好
what could I say well what can I say
这反映了这一事实
that that reflects the fact that that
这个lambda-没有抱歉
this lambda - no sorry
它反映了伽玛一个上升的人
it reflects so gamma one went up who
相机一个比lambda二大
camera one was bigger than lambda two
伽玛一号就是这里的重点
that was the point here gamma one is
更大，所以这很容易
bigger so so this was sort of easy
因为我正在添加我期望的东西
because I'm adding stuff I expected the
lambdas上去就是这个地方
lambdas to go up this is where the
定理是它到目前为止没有上升
theorem is that it didn't go up so far
至于传递或抱歉lambda二
as to pass or sorry the the lambda two
上升没有超过伽玛1
which went up didn't pass up gamma 1
lambda2现在没有通过gamma1
lambda 2 didn't pass up gamma 1 and now
让我把这些话写下来吧
let me write those words down now the
阿尔法2很好，它可以alpha
Alpha 2 well it could could alpha to
传递lambda1和alpha3怎么样
pass up lambda 1 and what about alpha 3
所以让我说出我相信的想法
so so let me say what I believe I think
alpha2就像1落后但是我
alpha 2 which is like 1 behind but I'm
添加排名-我认为alpha2可以通过
adding rank - I think alpha 2 could pass
lambda1它可以通过lambda1但是
up lambda 1 it could pass lambda 1 but
alpha3我不能相信alpha3
alpha 3 can't I believe that alpha 3 is
比lambda1小，所以alpha3更小
smaller than lambda 1 so alpha 3 smaller
然后伽玛不是原始的
than then then gamma wasn't the original
是的好哦，无论如何我会把它弄好
yeah okay Oh anyway I'll get it right in
你知道什么问题的笔记
the notes you you you know what question
我问，这对我来说就是那个
I'm asking and that's for me that's the
重要的事情
important thing
现在有一个小问题，为什么
now there is a little matter of why is
这是真的，这是好的情况让我
this true this is the good case let me
给你另一个隔行扫描的例子
give you another example of interlacing
我可以做到这就是真的
can I do that it's it's it it really
来自这个，但让我给你一个
comes from this but let me give you an
另一个例子就是这样我才引人注目
other example that's just striking so I
有一个对称矩阵n由n调用它
have a symmetric matrix n by n call it s
然后我扔掉了最后一排，并
and then I throw away the last row and
列所以在这里是sn减1大
column so in here is s n minus 1 the big
矩阵是SN，这是这个
matrix was SN the this is a this one is
大小为n减1可以，所以它有排序
of size n minus 1 okay so it's got sort
少自由度，因为
of less degrees of freedom because the
自由的最后度得到去除，
last degree of freedom got removed and
您如何看待特征值？
what do you think about the eigenvalues
这是N减1的特征值
of this the N minus 1 eigenvalues of
这和他们的n个特征值
this and the n eigenvalues of that they
交织所以这个特征值也是如此
interlace so the eigenvalues so so this
具有特征值lambda1
has eigen values lambda 1 this would
具有小于该特征值的特征值
have an eigenvalue smaller than that
这将有一个特征值lambda2
this would have an eigenvalue lambda 2
这将使特征值更小
this would have an eigenvalue smaller
比那样等等
than that and so on just the same
隔行扫描，基本上是相同的
interlacing and basically for the same
因为当你喜欢它的时候就像它一样
reason that when you like it's like it's
这就是这个减小到n的大小
this is this this reduction to size n
减1就像我说xn必须是
minus 1 is like I'm saying xn has to be
能量为0或任何一个
0 in the energy or any any of those
表达式和制作xn的事实
expressions and the fact of making xn be
0是一个约束1
0 is a like a 1 constraint taking one
它的自由度减少了
degree of freedom away it reduces the
特征值但不是两个好现在我
eigen values but not by two okay now I
有一个最后的神秘，让我尝试
have one final mystery and let me try to
告诉你它让我担心的是什么
tell you what it worried me no what is
它让我很担心
it that worried me yes
假设你这就是假设这个
suppose this you that supposes this
改变这种U该改变的是我
change this u this change that I'm
假设它实际上是第二个
making suppose it's actually the second
s的特征向量我也可以这样
eigenvector of s so so can I kind of
写下来
write this down
假设你实际上是第二个
suppose you is actually the second
s的特征向量我的意思是这样的
eigenvector of s where I mean by that so
我的意思是，有时U是lambda的2倍
I mean that s times U is lambda 2 times
ü还好还好，现在我看，我要去
u okay okay now I look at and I'm gonna
改变它s+uu转置那是什么
change it s + uu transpose that's what
我一直在看，这会让人感动
I've been looking at and that moves the
特征值上升但令我担心的是
eigenvalues up but what worries me is
就好像我把它乘以20大一些
like if I multiply this by 20 some big
我想要移动那个特征值
number I'm gonna move that eigenvalue
过去的方式我就像我担心的那样
way up way past I'm like I got worried
关于这个不平等的权利
about this this inequality right
如果我，但当我添加这就是那个
if I but when I add this that's that
相同的U是lambda2加20你写su
same U is lambda 2 plus 20 you write su
是lambda2u，这20是20U是
is lambda 2 u and this 20 is 20 U is a
单位矢量所以是的你在这里看到我的担心
unit vector so yes you see my worry here
我正在进行等级1更改，但它已被移动
I'm doing a Rank 1 change but it's moved
在特征值方式上如此可能
in eigen value way way up so how could
这种说法是真的，这种危险
this danger this this statement be true
所以我只是我只是想出了这里
so I'm just I've just figured out here
什么配得好呀
what what gamete well yeah
你看到我的问题，我可以把它留下来
you see my question I could leave it as
下次回答的问题让我这样做
a question to answer next time let me do
那个，我会把它放在网上，所以你会
that and I'll put it on online so you'll
看清楚它看起来像它
see it clearly it looks like and it it
发生这个特征向量现在有
happens that this eigen vector now has
特征值lambda2加20为什么不
eigen value lambda 2 plus 20 why doesn't
吹走这句话好吧，我会的
that blow away this statement okay I'll
把它放在一边，因为它有点来了
put that because it's sort of coming
与零下10秒，在去
with with minus 10 seconds to go in the
类，以便让我们离开那
class so so let's leave that
下次再讨论这个问题
a discussion of this for next time and
那么如果我对这个讲座感到满意的话
then but I'm happy with this lecture if
你是我使用V的最后一次演讲
you are the last lecture I got using V's
混淆了，我在这里不可靠
mixed up and it's not reliable here I
like the proof of D lambda DT and we're
就像DlambdaDT的证明一样，我们也是
从这个话题开始-非常感谢你
started on this topic - good thank you